officiallondontheatre.com 2019-12-19

# Privacy Policy - Official London Theatre

Official London Theatre is administered by Society of London Theatre a company registered in England and Wales (company number: 527227) whose registered office is at 32 Rose Street, London, WC2E 9ET (“SOLT”).

This Privacy Policy sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you or that you provide to us will be processed by us. Please read the following Privacy Policy to understand how we use and protect the information that you provide to us.

SOLT respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. It is important that you read this Privacy Policy together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This Privacy Policy supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.

 **Are you under 18? We have privacy policy just for you here.**

  * **1 Contacting SOLT**

For the purpose of UK data protection laws, the data controller in respect of any personal data that we collect about you or which you provide to us is SOLT. If you want to know what information we hold about you or if you have any other queries in relation to this Privacy Policy, our contact details are as follows:

Postal Address:

32 Rose Street

London

WC2E 9ET

Email: [enquiries@soltukt.co.uk](mailto:enquiries@soltukt.co.uk)

  2. **Data that we collect about you**

2.1 We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have explained using the following categories:

  * **Identity Data** includes first name, last name, job title and age.
  * **Contact Data** includes home address, company address, telephone and fax numbers, email address, billing contact details and billing address.
  * **Transaction Data** includes details about payments to and from you and other details of services you have purchased from us.
  * **Technical Data** includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website
  * **Profile Data** includes your username and password, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.
  * **Usage Data** includes information about how you use our website and services.
  * **Marketing and Communications Data** includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.

2.2 We may receive information that you submit to any third party website that you access from a link contained in this website, such as our ticketing agents, The Way Ahead Group Limited trading as SEE Tickets (“SEE”), when you purchase an Official London Theatre ticket. Both SOLT and the owner or operator of that third party website will be the data controller in respect of any such infotrmation and you should check the privacy policy of that website to find out how they will use your data. We will only use that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

2.3 Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with services). In this case, we may have to cancel a service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

2.4 We may collect information about your computer and your visits to our website and this may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type, length of visit and number of page views. We may use this information for a number of purposes such as optimising the use of the Site or for security purposes. In particular, we may use an analytics service provider for website traffic analysis and reporting and to track information such as which browser, screen resolution and IP address you are using to access our website, in addition to tracking your movements around our website. Individual users will not be identifiable from this information.

  3. **How we collect your data**

Generally we collect your information when you decide to interact with us.  We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

  * **Direct interactions**. You may give us your identity and contact data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise.
  * **Automated technologies or interactions**. As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect technical data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. We may also receive technical data about you if you visit other websites employing our cookies. Please see our [Cookies Usage Policy](https://officiallondontheatre.com/cookies/) for further details.
  * **Third parties or publicly available sources**. We may receive personal data about you from various third parties as set out below: 
    * Technical Data from analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU;
    * Identity, Contact and Transaction Data from SEE;
    * search information providers such as Companies House.

  4. **Use of Your Data**

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.
  * Where you have specifically consented to our use of the personal data, for example to sending direct marketing communications to you via email. You have the right to withdraw your consent to marketing at any time by contacting us.

  5. **Our policy on collecting data from children**

If you are a child, please read our privacy notice for children which sets out how we collect your data and what we do with it. ****

  6. **Purposes for which we will use your personal data**

We have set out in the table below a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate. Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data:

<!— TKTS – Added 7-9-18 —><!— TKTS – Added 7-9-18 —>

**Data used and purpose** | **Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest**  
---|---  
To register you as a user of our website we use your Identity and Contact, Profile & Marketing & Communications Data | Performance of a contract with you  
To process your purchase of a ticket we will use your Identity and Contact data | Performance of a contract with you  
To manage our relationship with you which will include: 

(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy

(b) Asking you to take a survey

we use your Identity, Contact, Profile and Marketing and Communications Data

| (a) Performance of a contract with you  
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated)  
To enable you to partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey we might use we use your Identity, Contact, Profile, Usage and Marketing and Communications Data | (a) Performance of a contract with you 

(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business)  
  
To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data) we might use your Identity, Contact, Usage, Profile and Technical Data (may include geographical & device type data or generalised personas based upon your likely browsing habits) | (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise) 

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you we use your Identity, Contact, Profile, Usage, Marketing and Communications and Technical Data | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how members use our services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences we use your Technical and Usage Data | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you we would use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)  
To promote and publicise Kids Week (where you have consented to our recording your image) we use your Identity Data | Consent  
To administer Kids Week activities we use your Identity Data | Necessary for our legitimate interests to run our events and activities  
In case we need to contact you about your booking after you purchase a ticket at TKTS, we will use your Identity and Contact Data | Performance of a contract with you  
To process your transaction when you purchase a ticket at TKTS we will use your Transaction Data | Performance of a contract with you  
  
  7. **Disclosure of your personal data**

7.1 Other than as expressly set out in this Privacy Policy or as otherwise required or permitted by law, we will not share, sell or distribute any of the information you provide to us without your express opt-in consent.

7.2 We may disclose your personal information to any person to whom disclosure is necessary to enable us to enforce our rights under this [Privacy Policy](https://officiallondontheatre.com/privacy/) or under the [Terms and Conditions](https://officiallondontheatre.com/terms/) or under our membership contract with you.  We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

7.3 If you have an account with Google and are signed in, Google may provide personalised advertising to you once you have left our website. See our [Cookies Usage Policy](https://officiallondontheatre.com/cookies/) for information on which Google cookies are being used on our website. Should you wish to opt-out of Google interest-based advertising you may do so here: [ **www.google.com/settings/ads**](http://www.google.com/settings/ads) or you can change your browser settings here: [ **optout.networkadvertising.org**](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

  8. **Opting out**

You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or, in respect of messages from us, by contacting us at any time. Should you wish us to stop sending you marketing emails you can update your preferences and unsubscribe from our emails [here](https://officiallondontheatre.com/newsletter/).

Please note that you will be automatically removed from our database if you haven’t opened an email from us for six months. You can opt-in again at any time.

  9. **Cookies**

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. Please see our [Cookies Usage Policy](http://solt.co.uk/cookie-policy/) for information on how we use cookies on our website.

  10. **Third party sites**

Our website may contain links to websites, plug-ins and applications that are operated by third parties.  Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you.  We do not control those websites and this Privacy Policy does not apply to those websites. Please consult the terms and conditions and privacy policy of those third party websites to find out how they collect and use your personal data and to establish whether and for what purpose they use cookies.

  11. **Data security**

11.1 We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality. However, you acknowledge that data transmission over the internet is inherently insecure and that we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the internet

11.2 We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

  12. Storing your data

12.1 We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

12.2 To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

12.3 Your information will only be held for a reasonable period or as long as the law requires or permits.

  13. **Third party processors**

13.1 The information that you provide to us will be collected and processed on our behalf by IBM Corporation (Watson Campaign Automation). For the avoidance of doubt, we may also have access to this information.

13.2 We may also share your information with service providers who work on behalf of SOLT for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you, for example payment processing, printers and mailing houses, marketing agencies, database services, website hosting or email delivery service.

  14. **International Data Transfers**

14.1 Your personal data may be transferred, processed and/or stored by us or our processors outside the European Economic Area (specifically the USA). By submitting your personal data, you agree to such transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

14.2 Some countries outside the EEA do not have laws that protect your privacy rights as extensively as those in the UK.  However, if we do transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we put in place appropriate safeguards to ensure that your personal data is properly protected and processed in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  These safeguards include imposing contract obligations of adequacy or requiring the recipient to subscribe to or be certified with an “international framework” of protection.

14.3 Please contact us if you would like further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

  15. **Your Rights**

15.1 Under certain circumstances you have rights under the UK data protection law in relation to your personal data as set out below. If you wish to exercise any such right in the appropriate circumstances, please contact us using the information provided above:

  * **Request access** to your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.
  * **Request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.
  * **Request erasure** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.
  * **Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.
  * **Request restriction of processing** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data’s accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.
  * **Request the transfer** of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.
  * **Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

15.2 You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

15.3 We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

15.4 We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

  16. **Changes to Our Privacy Policy and Your Duty to Inform us of Changes**

We reserve the right to make changes to the Privacy Policy from time to time. Any such changes to our Privacy Policy will be posted to our website.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current.  Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

 **Last updated: 7 September 2018**

##  **SOLT/UK Theatre Privacy Policy for Kids and Young People**

We are the Society of London Theatre and we want you let you know how we use information about you when you sign up to receive one of our newsletters on our website.

 **Why do we collect information about you in the first place?**

We keep information about you so that we can:

  * let you have the newsletter you signed up for
  * make our website and the things we offer better
  * keep in touch with you, for example, to ask you if you want to carry on receiving our newsletter
  * where your parents have agreed on your behalf, use your image to promote Kids Week.

**We’ll always tell you why we’re collecting your personal information**

We’ll explain why and how we use it and for how long. It’s called a “privacy notice”. And if we need your parent or guardian’s permission we’ll give you clear details about what’s needed at the time.

 **We can only use your personal information if we have a valid reason.**

In this case, because we got your permission when you signed up for our newsletter.

 **What information do we have about you?**

Your name, your email address and your date of birth.

 **We may share personal information about you with others if we need them to help us process or store it, but we  follow some rules. **

We never sell your personal information to anyone.

 **We might ask you to tell us your date of birth**

This is so we know how old you are and can ask permission from your parent or guardian to sign you up for our newsletter.

If we ask for your parent or guardian’s permission, we will let you know.

 **It’s safe to use us**

It’s our job to keep the personal information we collect from you safe and secure and we have systems in place to make sure that we do that.

 **You’re in control of how we use cookies and tracking**

Cookies are bits of data that are stored on your phone, tablet or computer. Some things on our websites wouldn’t be able to work without these cookies.

We use cookies and tracking to make our website better and to provide content that is relevant for you.

You can turn off some cookies and similar tracking technologies. See our cookies policy for how to do this.  Or your parent or guardian can do this if you’re under 13.

 **You’ve got privacy rights, the same as adults, so get to know what they are**

In some cases you can:

  * ask us what personal information we hold about you
  * ask us to correct or delete your personal information
  * tell us to stop using your personal information at any time.

Please contact us by emailing us at [enquiries@soltukt.co.uk](mailto:enquiries@soltukt.co.uk) if you would like to do any of these things.

 **What if you change your mind?**

If you change your mind and you don’t want to receive our newsletter any more, you can let us know by emailing us at: [enquiries@soltukt.co.uk](mailto:enquiries@soltukt.co.uk).  Each time we send you our newsletter, you’ll get the chance to ask us to stop sending it to you by clicking on the button that says “Unsubscribe”. That means we won’t send you the newsletter any more.

 **If you have any questions** , you can always contact us at [enquiries@soltukt.co.uk](mailto:enquiries@soltukt.co.uk) _._

Last updated: 7 July 2018
